Jesper Kjeldgaard



thejspr@gmail.com +44 07869756423

I'm an experienced developer with a passion for solving problems using software, prefer doing to talking and do not consider something done before it is shipped. I like the process of solving problems from start to finish, including design and UX through to AB testing and performance optimization. I have close to two years of professional Rails experience, and have worked with Ruby for about 3 years.

I'm always looking for new things that increase productivity and simplify development, which led me to start learning Ruby and Rails in 2010. I strive to write simple, efficient and maintainable code, as well as improve on existing implementations. I'm confident, and take pleasure, in learning new technologies and concepts, and I'm currently looking into Clojure, Design, iOS & HTML5 outside of work.

Experience

HouseTrip, Software Developer. April 2013 - Current

At HouseTrip I work on adding and improving features in a large Rails e-commerce web-application.

Evently, Software Engineer. November 2011 - March 2013 (1 year 5 months)

At Evently I have worked on making online event marketing easier. This includes adding features to and maintaining a large SaaS Rails application, and building new API consuming/providing applications. The technologies I used whilst at Evently include: Redis, MongoDB, RSpec, SOA, EC2/Heroku, Postgresql and EmberJS.

One project I've worked on whilst at Evently was a service to distribute events to numerous listing sites using Capybara. Another project was creating <u>public event pages</u> for events. The public event pages are managed from a separate application which updates the pages through an API. Most projects were developed using Kanban.

Evently used to have 10% time, in which I developed several business <u>related prototypes</u>.

Harmonypark, Intern. March 2011 – September 2011 (7 months)

At Harmonypark I worked on a large time management Rails application and learned a lot about BDD and working with large applications.

Capana, Student Developer. May 2009 - September 2010 (1 year 5 months)

Developing web applications internally and for customers using PHP and MySQL. I worked on a 2-person team and delivered a work planning application for a large telephone company.

Education

MSc Internet Application Development. October 2010 - November 2011

Middlesex University, London, United Kingdom

Grade: 2:1 (Pass with Merit)

Notable projects: Web server (Ruby). Web-based file storage service (PHP).

BSc. Software Engineering. September 2007 - June 2010

Aalborg University, Aalborg, Denmark

Grade: B average. A in my final project.

Notable projects: An Implicit parallel programming language (Java). A social network for

universities (C#/ASP.NET).

Technical Skills Summary

- Languages: Ruby, JavaScript (+CoffeeScript).
- Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Sinatra and EmberJS.
- Databases: Postgresql, MongoDB, Redis and Mysql.
- Platforms: EC2 and Heroku.
- Testing: RSpec, Cucumber and Jasmine.
- Methodologies: XP, Kanban and Scrum.
- Msc: *nix, HTML and CSS.

Above are the technologies I currently use but I also have knowledge of Java, PHP, C#, ASP.NET and Haskell.

More information

thejspr.com github.com/thejspr linkedin.com/in/jesperkjeldgaard